Chandler, Alfred D., 1918-2007. Papers, 1941-2004: A Finding Aid
Alfred D. Chandler papers, 1940-2007
- Series III. Harvard Business School (HBS), Active Tenure, 1968-1991
  - Subseries B. HBS Correspondence and Subject Files, Transition, 1978-1991
    - Clarke, John, 1990 (Box 98, f. 8)
    - Cochran, Sherman, 1988 (Box 98, f. 9)
    - Cochran, Pro Thomas C., 1989 (Box 98, f. 10)
    - Cohen, Isaac, 1988-1990 (Box 98, f. 11)
    - Cohen, Lizabeth, 1988 (Box 98, f. 12)
    - Conference: Reimbursement of Expenses, 1990 (Box 98, f. 13)
    - Consortium on Competitiveness and Cooperation, 1990 (Box 98, f. 14)
    - Coway, Jill, 1988 (Box 98, f. 15)
    - Contrada, James W., 1990 (Box 98, f. 16)
    - Covington and Burling, 1990 (Box 98, f. 17)
    - Cox, Annette, 1988 (Box 98, f. 18)
    - Crawford, FrederickC, 1989 (Box 98, f. 19)
    - Cunningham, Steve (Salem Boys and Girls Club), 1989 (Box 98, f. 20)
    - Czikowsky, Leon, 1990 (Box 98, f. 21)
    - D: Department of History (U Michigan-Ann Arbor)-Doorley (Box 98, f. 22)
    - Dale, Ernest, 1990 (Box 98, f. 23)
    - David, Paul, 1988 (Box 98, f. 24)
    - Deitering, Anne-Marie, 1989 (Box 98, f. 25)
    - Davis, Colin J., 1989 (Box 98, f. 26)
    - Developmental Management, 1989 (Box 98, f. 27)
    - Didrichsen, Jon, 1988 (Box 98, f. 28)
    - Dioguardi, Gianfranco, 1988-1990 (Box 98, f. 29)
    - Donaldson, Lex, 1990 (Box 98, f. 30)
    - Drucker, Peter, 1989 (Box 98, f. 31)
    - Dunlavy, Coleen, 1988-1990 (Box 98, f. 32)
    - Dupree, A. Hunter, 1988 (Box 98, f. 33)
    - E: Erdman - Economic Policy Institute, 1991 (Box 98, f. 34)
    - Economics Management Theories and Behavior Science, etc.: Lorsch/Etozioni Seminar, 1987-1988 (Box 98, f. 35)
    - Electronics USA: April Neilson, ed., 1989-1990 (Box 98, f. 36)
    - Elgar, Edward, 1989 (Box 98, f. 37)
    - Encyclopedia of American Social History: Charles Schribner’s, 1990 (Box 98, f. 38)
    - Erenkotter, Donald, 1990 (Box 98, f. 39)
    - Espania, Alvaro (Ministerio De Trabajo Y Seguridad Social), 1990 (Box 98, f. 40)
    - Etzioni, Pro Amitai, 1984-1990 (Box 98, f. 41)
    - Executive Book Summaries, 1989 (Box 98, f. 42)
    - F: Ferris, M.P. - Foreman, Steve, 1990 (Box 99, f. 1)
    - Feldenkirchen, Wilfried, 1988-1990 (Box 99, f. 2)
    - Ferrier, Ronald W., 1989-1990 (Box 99, f. 3)
    - Fin de Siècle, 1988-1989 (Box 99, f. 4)
    - Finley, George E., 1988 (Box 99, f. 5)
    - Firm Taskforce, 1988 (Box 99, f. 6)
    - Figstein, Neil, 1990 (Box 99, f. 7)
    - Fogel, Robert, 1990 (Box 99, f. 8)
    - Fortune, 1990 (Box 99, f. 9)
    - Free Press, 1990 (Box 99, f. 10)
    - Freeland, Richard, 1988-1990 (Box 99, f. 11)
    - Fridenson, Patrick, 1985-1988 (Box 99, f. 12)
    - Fridenson, Patrick: Articles for Revue Francise de Gestion, undated (Box 99, f. 13)
    - Funkhouser, G. Ray, 1989 (Box 99, f. 14)
    - Fursenko, A.A., 1988 (Box 99, f. 15)
    - G: Garcia-Haras - Green, 1988-1990 (Box 99, f. 16)
    - Galambos, Louis, 1987-1990 (Box 99, f. 17)
    - Galison, Peter, 1988-1990 (Box 99, f. 18)
    - Garcia, Linda, 1988 (Box 99, f. 19)
    - German Marshall Fund of the U.S., 1989-1990 (Box 99, f. 20)
    - Gibb, George, 1989 (Box 99, f. 21)
    - Goodell, Grace, 1989 (Box 99, f. 22)
    - Graphic Chronologies, 1989 (Box 99, f. 23)
    - Graham, Pauline, 1988 (Box 99, f. 24)
    - Great Northern History: Hidy and Hidy, 1987-1988 (Box 99, f. 25)
    - Gunderson, Gerald, 1989 (Box 99, f. 26)
    - H: Hast - Hundt, 1990 (Box 99, f. 27)
    - Hall, Max, 1986-1988 (Box 99, f. 28)
    - Hammond, Thomas H., 1988 (Box 99, f. 29)
    - Hannah, Leslie, 1988-1990 (Box 99, f. 30)
    - Harvard Club: New York, 1988 (Box 99, f. 31)
    - Harvard University Graduate School of Education, 1990 (Box 99, f. 32)
    - Hay, David Lowell, 1987 (Box 99, f. 33)
    - Hausman, William, 1990 (Box 99, f. 34)
    - Hayman, Shelia, 1988 (Box 99, f. 35)
    - Henderson, Alexa B., 1988 (Box 99, f. 36)
    - Hennart, Jean-Francois, 1985-1988 (Box 99, f. 37)
    - Heras, Raul Garcia, 1988 (Box 99, f. 38)
    - Hertenstein, Julie H., 1990 (Box 99, f. 39)
    - Hertner, Peter, 1990 (Box 99, f. 40)
    - Higgins, Mary, 1989 (Box 99, f. 41)
    - Holland, Max, 1991 (Box 99, f. 42)
    - Hollingsworth, J. Roger, 1987-1989 (Box 99, f. 43)
    - Holtz, R.T., 1990 (Box 99, f. 44)
    - Hopper, Kenneth, 1985-1990 (Box 99, f. 45)
    - Horwitch, Mel, 1986-1988 (Box 99, f. 46)
    - Horowitz, Irving Louis, 1989-1990 (Box 99, f. 47)
    - Hounshell, David; 1985-1988 (Box 99, f. 48)
    - Huber, Peter W., 1988 (Box 99, f. 49)
    - Hughes, Thomas, undated (Box 99, f. 50)
    - Hurlburt, Robert, 1988 (Box 99, f. 51)
    - I: Institute of International Business (Box 100, f. 1)
    - International Review of Comparative Public Policy, 1988 (Box 100, f. 2)
    - Investing Strategy, 1989 (Box 100, f. 3)
    - Richard D. Irwin Publishers, Inc., 1989-1990 (Box 100, f. 4)
    - Isley, Jeter A., 1988 (Box 100, f. 5)
    - Instituto Della Enciclopedia Italiena: Pro V. Cappelletti, 1989 (Box 100, f. 6)
    - J: Jeffery, Mrs. Louise: Johns Hopkins University Press, 1990 (Box 100, f. 7)
    - Jackson, Gregory, 1989 (Box 100, f. 8)
    - Japan Academy, The, 1990 (Box 100, f. 9)
    - Japan and Europe: List of Companies, undated (Box 100, f. 10)
    - Jenkins, Reese, V., 1989 (Box 100, f. 11)
    - Johns Hopkins, 1990 (Box 100, f. 12)
    - Journal of Accounting and Economics, 1988 (Box 100, f. 13)
    - Jones, Geoffrey, 1988-1990 (Box 100, f. 14)
    - Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 1986-1990 (Box 100, f. 15)
    - Journal of Industrial and Corporate Change, 1988 (Box 100, f. 16)
    - K: Kawabe - Kluge, 1989-1990 (Box 100, f. 17)
    - Kapstein, Ethan B., 1987-1990 (Box 100, f. 18)
    - KCET TV, 1988 (Box 100, f. 19)
    - Kohane, Robert O., 1985 (Box 100, f. 20)
    - Kerr, Austin K., 1987-1990 (Box 100, f. 21)
    - Kindleberger, Charles P., 1986 (Box 100, f. 22)
    - Kobayashi, Kesaji, 1988 (Box 100, f. 23)
    - Kochevrin, Yuri, 1990 (Box 100, f. 24)
    - Kocka, Jürgan, 1990 (Box 100, f. 25)
    - Kranakis, Eda, 1988 (Box 100, f. 26)
    - Kranzberg, Melvin, 1985-1991 (Box 100, f. 27)
    - Kuwahara, Tetsuya, 1987-1988 (Box 100, f. 28)
    - L: Langer - Luthans, 1989-1990 (Box 100, f. 29)
    - Landes, David, 1988-1990 (Box 100, f. 30)
    - Landmark Communications, Inc., 1989 (Box 100, f. 31)
    - Landry, John, 1990 (Box 100, f. 32)
    - Langstaff, David H., 1989 (Box 100, f. 33)
    - Leff, Nathanial H., 1989 (Box 100, f. 34)
    - Lessum, Ronnie, 1989 (Box 100, f. 35)
    - Levy-Leboyer, Maurice, 1988-1989 (Box 100, f. 36)
    - Lewis, Clifford, 1988 (Box 100, f. 37)
    - Lewis, Dr. David L. (Re: Ford Motor), 1988 (Box 100, f. 38)
    - Lexington Group, 1989 (Box 100, f. 39)
    - Libecap, Gary D., 1989 (Box 100, f. 40)
    - Life Magazine, 1990 (Box 100, f. 41)
    - Light, David W, 1985 (Box 100, f. 42)
    - Lindgren, Seth, 1989 (Box 100, f. 43)
    - Little, Kevin, 1988 (Box 100, f. 44)
    - Livingston, James, 1990 (Box 100, f. 45)
    - Lodge, George, 1985-1989 (Box 100, f. 46)
    - Loescher, Samuel M., 1987-1988 (Box 100, f. 47)
    - Lorsch, Jay W., 1988 (Box 100, f. 48)
    - Lovett, Robert W., 1988 (Box 100, f. 49)
    - Low, Nathan A., 1989 (Box 100, f. 50)
    - McArthur, John H., Dean, 1985-1989 (Box 100, f. 51)
    - McKenna, Christopher D., 1990 (Box 100, f. 52)
    - McKenna, James, 1990 (Box 100, f. 53)
    - MacKinnon, William P., 1988 (Box 100, f. 54)
    - M: MFS Service Center, Inc.-Madison, 1989-1990 (Box 100, f. 55)
    - Made in U.S.A.: PBS Telecourse Series, 1989-1990 (Box 100, f. 56)
    - Magnetic Arts, 1988-1989 (Box 101, f. 1)
    - Marchand, Roland, 1989 (Box 101, f. 2)
    - Markiewicz, Patrice, 1988 (Box 101, f. 3)
    - Martin, Kenneth R., undated (Box 101, f. 4)
    - Mathis, Franz, 1986-1988 (Box 101, f. 5)
    - Mathur, Navin, 1988-1990 (Box 101, f. 6)
    - Metha, Shailendra Raj, 1988 (Box 101, f. 7)
    - Meijer, Hendrik, 1985 (Box 101, f. 8)
    - Merck and Company, 1990 (Box 101, f. 9)
    - Merrill Lynch, 1988 (Box 101, f. 10)
    - Migliori, Sante, 1989 (Box 101, f. 11)
    - Moss, Scott, 1987-1990 (Box 101, f. 12)
    - Motelay, Patrick, 1989 (Box 101, f. 13)
    - Murphy, Antoin, 1988-1990 (Box 101, f. 14)
    - N: Nagel-Nielsen, 1988-1990 (Box 101, f. 15)
    - National Academy of Engineering, 1988 (Box 101, f. 16)
    - National Geographic Society, 1988-1989 (Box 101, f. 17)
    - Neufeld, E.P., 1988 (Box 101, f. 18)
    - Neuhauser, John, 1988 (Box 101, f. 19)
    - New England Quarterly, 1990-1991 (Box 101, f. 20)
    - Newman, Peter, 1990 (Box 101, f. 21)
    - North Carolina University Press, 1988-1989 (Box 101, f. 22)
    - O’Brien, Anthony Patrick, 1989-1990 (Box 101, f. 23)
    - P: Tom Peters Group, The-Pütz, 1989-1990 (Box 101, f. 24)
    - Paragon, 1988 (Box 101, f. 25)
    - Permissions, 1989 (Box 101, f. 26)
    - Pfeiffer, Jeffrey, 1988 (Box 101, f. 27)
    - Pine, Carol, 1990 (Box 101, f. 28)
    - Phol, Hans, 1988 (Box 101, f. 29)
    - Pool, Adam de Sola, 1988 (Box 101, f. 30)
    - Poor Papers, 1989 (Box 101, f. 31)
    - Poorvu, William J., 1989 (Box 101, f. 32)
    - Porter, Michael E., 1988 (Box 101, f. 33)
    - Porter Project on Underinvestment, 1990 (Box 101, f. 34)
    - Porter, Roy, 1990 (Box 101, f. 35)
    - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1989-1989 (Box 101, f. 36)
    - Previts, Gary, 1988 (Box 101, f. 37)
    - Princeton University Press, 1988 (Box 101, f. 38)
    - Q: Quigley, Dr. N.C.-Quinn Mills, Pro D, 1989-1990 (Box 101, f. 39)
    - R: Raymond-Rea, 1990-1991 (Box 101, f. 40)
    - Ranki Prize, 1989-1991 (Box 101, f. 41)
    - Rasusen, Eric, 1989 (Box 101, f. 42)
    - Rassbach, Elsa, 1989-1990 (Box 101, f. 43)
    - Reader, William J., 1988-1990 (Box 101, f. 44)
    - Readers’ Encyclopedia of American History, Houghton Mifflin Company, The, 1988-1990 (Box 101, f. 45)
    - Redlich Prize, 1989 (Box 101, f. 46)
    - Reich, Robert, 1988 (Box 101, f. 47)
    - Reid, Donald, 1988 (Box 101, f. 48)
    - Research Policy Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 101, f. 49)
    - Ross, Bruce, 1988 (Box 101, f. 50)
    - Rostow, Walt W., 1990 (Box 101, f. 51)
    - Rothstein, Morton, 1985 (Box 101, f. 52)
    - Ruph, Immo, 1989 (Box 101, f. 53)
    - S: Sage Publications, Inc.-Sutch, 1989-1990 (Box 102, f. 1)
    - Sahlman, William, 1988 (Box 102, f. 2)
    - Salsbury, Stephen, 1987 (Box 102, f. 3)
    - Saussois, Jean Michel, 1989 (Box 102, f. 4)
    - Scale and Scope, 1989-1990 (Box 102, f. 5)
    - Scale and Scope Transactions, 1990 (Box 102, f. 6)
    - Schroter, H.G., 1990 (Box 102, f. 7)
    - Schweber, Silvan, S., 1989 (Box 102, f. 8)
    - Scott, Bruce, 1988 (Box 102, f. 9)
    - Scott, W. Richard, 1988 (Box 102, f. 10)
    - Scott, Forseman and Company, 1989 (Box 102, f. 11)
    - Seamans, Robert, 1989 (Box 102, f. 12)
    - Segal, Joanne, 1989 (Box 102, f. 13)
    - Shell Oil, 1988 (Box 102, f. 14)
    - Sibley, Katherine, A.S., 1988 (Box 102, f. 15)
    - Simpson, Sally, 1989 (Box 102, f. 16)
    - Skinner, Wick, undated (Box 102, f. 17)
    - Slater, Robert O., 1988 (Box 102, f. 18)
    - Sobel, Robert, 1989 (Box 102, f. 19)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1988 (Box 102, f. 20)
    - Social Thought, 1989 (Box 102, f. 21)
    - Stauffenberg, Phillip V., 1988 (Box 102, f. 22)
    - Stevenson, Howard H., 1988 (Box 102, f. 23)
    - Stinchcombe, Arthur L., 1988 (Box 102, f. 24)
    - Stobaugh, Robert, 1988 (Box 102, f. 25)
    - Strasser, Susan, 1985-1988 (Box 102, f. 26)
    - Strategy and Structure -MIT Contracts-Promotions/Permissions, 1989-1989 (Box 102, f. 27)
    - Strategy and Structure -French Edition, 1989 (Box 102, f. 26)
    - Strouse, Jean, 1988-1990 (Box 102, f. 29)
    - Strozier, Charles B., 1989 (Box 102, f. 30)
    - Sutton, John, 1990 (Box 102, f. 31)
    - Swedberg, Richard, 1989 (Box 102, f. 32)
    - T: Taffel-Twist, 1989-1990 (Box 102, f. 33)
    - Taylor, Marilyn L., 1988 (Box 102, f. 34)
    - Teich, Milulas and Porter, Roy - Roy vol. "Fin de Siecle and its Legacy," 1988-1990 (Box x102, f. 35)
    - Telser, Lester G, 1988 (Box 102, f. 36)
    - Temin, Peter, 1986 (Box 102, f. 37)
    - Thompson, Greg, 1988 (Box 102, f. 38)
    - Thompson, Ross, 1989-1990 (Box 102, f. 39)
    - Trevor, Leigh B., 1989 (Box 102, f. 40)
    - U: Ullenhag-University Press of New England, 1990 (Box 102, f. 41)
    - U.S. Air Force-Advisory Committee, 1988 (Box 102, f. 42)
    - United Technologies-United News Journal, 1990 (Box 102, f. 43)
    - University Publications, Inc., 1988-1989 (Box 102, f. 44)
    - Unwin Hyman Limited, 1989 (Box 102, f. 45)
    - Vancil, Richard, 1989 (Box 102, f. 46)
    - Van der Ven, Andrew H., 1990 (Box 102, f. 47)
    - Van Druen, Leonard, 1990 (Box 102, f. 48)
    - Verenkotte, Clemens, 1988-1989 (Box 102, f. 49)
    - Veitor, Richard, H.K., 1990 (Box 102, f. 50)
    - Viking Penguin, Inc., 1988-1989 (Box 103, f. 1)
    - The Visible Hand Royalties, 1985 (Box 103, f. 2)
    - The Visible Hand Chinese Edition, 1987-1988 (Box 103, f. 3)
    - The Visible Hand French Edition, 1986-1988 (Box 103, f. 4)
    - The Visible Hand Japanese Introduction,1981-1986 (Box 103, f. 5)
    - The Visible Hand Spanish Edition, 1988 (Box 103, f. 6)
    - W: Wallman-Wirtschafts Woche, 1989-1990 (Box 103, f. 7)
    - WGBH Series on Business History-Bob Gebelle, 1989 (Box 103, f. 8)
    - Wall, Bennett, 1988-1990 (Box 103, f. 9)
    - Widebock, Goran, 1989 (Box 103, f. 10)
    - Wiedersheim, William, 1989 (Box 103, f. 11)
    - Wiley, John-Publisher Ltd., 1985 (Box 103, f. 12)
    - Wilkins, Mira, 1988-1990 (Box 103, f. 13)
    - Williamson, Oliver E., 1987-1989 (Box 103, f. 14)
    - Wilson Center: The Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1989 (Box 103, f. 15)
    - Wilson, Steve, 1989 (Box 103, f. 16)
    - Winthrop Research Group, Inc. and Others, 1988-1990 (Box 103, f. 17)
    - Witherby, Frederick, 1990 (Box 103, f. 18)
    - Wojtecki, Joseph G., 1988 (Box 103, f. 19)
    - Wolf, Bernard, M., 1988 (Box 103, f. 20)
    - Wray, William D., 1988 (Box 103, f. 21)
    - Wright, John S., 1989 (Box 103, f. 22)
    - Yeager (Kujovich), Mary, 1989-1990 (Box 103, f. 23)
    - Yoffie, David B., 1987 (Box 103, f. 24)
    - Yoshino, Michael, 1987-1988 (Box 103, f. 25)
    - Yui, Tsunehiko, 1988 (Box 103, f. 26)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1978-1986 (Box 103, f. 27)
  - Subseries C. HBS Research and Writing, General, 1970-1988
    This subseries consists of research and writing projects undertaken by Alfred Chandler during his time as a professor at HBS. The material includes research notes, photocopies of primary and secondary research material, newspaper clippings, corrected drafts, and correspondence concerning the works, including comments from others who read Chandler's manuscripts.
    This subseries includes material related to The Visible Hand which was published in 1977 (additional material related to The Visible Hand can also be found in Series II); and materials related to Scale and Scope: the Dynamics of Industrial Capitalism which was published in 1990. The latter includes photocopied records on many business firms, including material from the library of Imperial Chemicals, Ltd., London, 1919-1968, consisting of memos, letters, minutes, reports, addresses, and charts detailing the organization and method of operation.
    Also included are records from Boots, Ltd., 1920-1978, including minutes and reports; materials from Unilever, 1922-1939, including minutes and Alfred Chandler's notes; material from the Siemens archives; and material on General Electric and Allegemeine Elektricitaets Gesellscaff from the Owen D. Young Papers, 1926-1930. Owen D. Young was the president of General Electric.
    Arranged chronologically by project and date of publication. The date of creation sometimes predates Chandler's tenure at HBS. There is some undated material, which has been placed at the beginning of the series.
    - Oligopoly and Vertical Integration, undated (Box 104, f. 1)
    - McGovern Manuscript, undated (Box 104, f. 2)
    - Notes on Diesel, undated (Box 104, f. 3)
    - Eisenhower Papers, Correspondence, 1971 (Box 104, f. 4)
    - Eisenhower Papers: Chronology (Box 104, f. 5-8)
    - Eisenhower Papers: Galley Changes (Box 104, f. 9)
    - Eisenhower Papers: Notes (Box 104, f. 10)
    - Eisenhower Papers: Articles and Reviews, 1970-1982 (Box 104, f. 11)
    - Coal, Steam and Iron...[pub. as "Anthracite Coal and the Beginnings of the Industrial Revolution in the United States", 1972 (Box 104, f. 12-18)
    - Introduction to State Papers on Manufacturing [pub. 1972] (Box 105, f. 1-5)
    - Introduction to State Papers on Manufacturing -Research [pub. 1972] (Box 105, f. 6-8)
    - Introduction to State Papers on Manufacturing -Notes, drafts, etc. [pub. 1972] (Box 105, f. 9-12)
    - "Henry Varnum Poor" (Encyclopedia of Notable Americans), circa 1973 (Box 106, f. 1)
    - "Prospectus for a Project to Study the History of Large-Scale Business Enterprise in Major Market Economies", 1973 (Box 106, f. 2)
    - "The Businessman: An American Cultural Hero", 1974 (Box 106, f. 3)
    - "The Rise of Large-Scale Business Enterprise and the Coming of the New Deal", 1974 (Box 106, f. 4)
    - "Structure and Investment Decisions in the U.S.: 19th-20th Centuries" (Box 106, f. 5-8)
    - "John Jacob Raskob" (DAB) [pub. 1974] (Box 106, f. 9)
    - Raskob Research Material [pub. 1974] (Box 106, f. 15)
    - "The Multi-Unit Enterprise ..." [pub. 1975] (Box 106, f. 16-23)
    - "The Chief Executive's Office in Historical Perspective" [pub. 1976] (Box 106, f. 21-23)
    - "The Development of Modern Management Structures," [pub. in 1976] (Box 107, f. 1-5)
    - "Institutional Integration ..." [pub. 1976] (Box 107, f. 6-7)
    - Reviews, 1977-1978 (Box 107, f. 8)
    - "Pierre S. du Pont" [pub. 1977] (Box 107, f. 9)
    - The Visible Hand [pub. 1977] Chapter 2 (Box 107, f. 10-12)
    - The Visible Hand: Data for Chapter 2 (Box 107, f. 13-17)
    - The Visible Hand: Ed Perkins' Data for Chapter 3 (Box 107, f. 18)
    - The Visible Hand: Chapter 5 (Box 107, f. 19)
    - The Visible Hand: Material for Manufacturing and Railroads Chapters (Box 107, f. 20)
    - The Visible Hand: "The Business Revolution," Thomas Cochran (Box 107, f. 21)
    - The Visible Hand: "The Evolution of American Industrial Management, 1795-1833" (Box 108, f. 1)
    - The Visible Hand: Photocopies of 18th Century Accounts (Box 108, f. 2)
    - The Visible Hand: Notes for Part II (Box 108, f. 3-6)
    - The Visible Hand: Part of Railroad Chapter (Box 108, f. 7)
    - The Visible Hand: Corrections Made in England: Introduction and Chapter 1 (Box 108, f. 8)
    - The Visible Hand: Corrections Made in England: Chapter 2 (Box 108, f. 9)
    - The Visible Hand: Corrections Made in England: Chapters 3 and 4 (Box 108, f. 10)
    - The Visible Hand: Corrections Made in England: Chapters 5 and 7 (Box 108, f. 11)
    - The Visible Hand: Book Reviews, August 1977-Spring 1978 (Box 108, f. 12)
    - The Visible Hand: Book Reviews, April 1978-Summer 1978 (Box 108, f. 13)
    - The Visible Hand: Book Reviews, July 1978-Summer 1979 (Box 108, f. 14)
    - The Visible Hand: Book Reviews, July 1979-1982 (Box 108, f. 15)
    - The Visible Hand: Bancroft and Pulitzer Prizes, March-April 1978 (Box 108, f. 16)
    - The Visible Hand: Bancroft and Pulitzer Prizes, May-August 1978 (Box 108, f. 17)
    - The Visible Hand: Congratulations, 1977-1978 (Box 108, f. 18)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise [pub. 1977]: Correspondence (Box 108, f. 19)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Chapter 1 Data (Box 108, f. 20)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Chapter 2, Part 1 Data (Box 108, f. 21)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Chapters 3 and 4 Data (Box 108, f. 22-23)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Rough Draft (Box 109, f. 1)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Final Rough Draft (Box 109, f. 2-4)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Preliminary Draft (Box 109, f. 5)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Draft (Box 109, f. 6-7)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Sarah Fave Data (Box 109, f. 8)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: 1860 Census (Box 109, f. 9-10)
    - The United States: Evolution of Enterprise: Printed Pages (Box 109, f. 11)
    - Reply to Thomas R. Winpenny re: "Anthracite Coal and the Beginnings of the Industrial Revolution ..." [pub. 1979] (Box 109, f. 12)
    - "The Rise and Evolution of Big Business" [pub. 1980] (Box 109, f. 13-16)
    - Managerial Hierarchies: General, 1978-1980 (Box 110, f. 1-2)
    - Managerial Hierarchies [pub. 1980]: Book Reviews, 1980-1982 (Box 110, f. 3)
    - "Historical Determinants and Managerial Hierarchies" [pub. 1981]: Correspondence (Box 110, f. 4)
    - "Historical Determinants and Managerial Hierarchies": Drafts (Box 110, f. 5-7)
    - "Historical Determinants and Managerial Hierarchies": Final Draft (Box 110, f. 8)
    - "The M-Form- Industrial Groups, American Style" [pub. 1982] (Box 110, f. 9-10)
    - Introduction to Rise of the Corporate Economy, by Leslie Hannah: [Intro. written 1983] (Box 110, f. 11)
    - "Comparative Business History" [pub. 1984] (Box 110, f. 12)
    - "Evolution of Global Competition" [pub. 1986] (Box 110, f. 13)
    - "Evolution of Global Competition" Notes and Correspondence (Box 110, f. 14)
    - "The Beginnings of the Modern Industrial Corporation" [pub. 1986] (Box 110, f. 15)
    - "Technology and Transformation of Industrial Organization" [1987] (Box 110, f. 16)
    - "Alfred P. Sloan, Jr." [circa 1987] (Box 110, f. 17)
    - Scale and Scope: Correspondence, 1978-1986 (Box 110, f. 18)
    - Scale and Scope: Correspondence: Comments on Chapter 1, 1982-1983 (Box 111, f. 1)
    - Scale and Scope: Daems, Herman: Correspondence and Data, 1980-1985 (Box 111, f. 2-6)
    - Scale and Scope: Hannah, Leslie: Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 111, f. 7)
    - Scale and Scope: Williamson, Oliver: Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 111, f. 8-11)
    - Scale and Scope: Whitney, Dorothy (Harvard University Press) Correspondence, 1989 (Box 234, f. 1)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 1-6 (1-5), Sept. 1988 (Box 234, f. 2)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 1 (Old Copy) (Box 111, f. 12)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 2 (Old Copy) (Box 111, f. 13)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 2 (Final, 4-3) (Box 111, f. 14)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 2 (Box 234, f. 3)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (8-7-80) (Box 111, f. 15)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (7-31-81 Version) (Box 111, f. 16-17)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (8-12-83) (Box 112, f. 1)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (Out of Date) (Box 112, f. 2)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (5-6-85) (Box 112, f. 3)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (7-11-85) (Box 112, f. 4)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (1-9-86) (Box 112, f. 5)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (Corrected, 1-9-86) (Box 112, f. 6)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 3 (Box 234, f. 4)
    - Scale and Scope: Tables for Chapters 3 and 4 (Box 234, f. 5)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 4 (1983 Version) (Box 112, f. 7)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 4 (1-15-86) (Box 112, f. 8)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 4 (Corrected, 1-15-86) (Box 112, f. 9)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 4 (Box 234, f. 6)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 5 (undated) (Box 112, f. 10)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 5 (1983 Version) (Box 112, f. 11)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 5 (Old Version, 3-3-86) (Box 112, f. 12-13)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 5 (Box 234, f. 7)
    - Scale and Scope: Consumer Chemicals - The British Experience (A Version of Chapter 5) (Box 112, f. 14)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 6 (Box 234, f. 8)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 7 (8-81) (Box 112, f. 15)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 7 (Box 234, f. 9-10)
    - Scale and Scope: Chapter 8 (Box 234, f. 11-12)